# **IBRAHIM ABDULGANIYU**

Lagos, Lagos State, Nigeria



abdulganiyutechng@gmail.com



07039901318



linkedin.com/in/ibrahimxtech



https://abdulganiyu.vercel.app

## Summary

Summary

Experience: 3 years of total experience, with a focus on Full-stack (MERN) web/mobile engineering.

Skills: Proficient in Javascript, Typescript, React, React Native, Redux, Redux toolkit Query, GraphQL, NodeJs, Express, and MongoDb.

Experienced in all stages of advanced web/mobile development, from design and installation to testing and maintenance. Skilled in user interface and API development, testing, and debugging.

### Career Highlights:

Led the successful development and launch of a customer-facing mobile app, resulting in a 30% increase in user engagement and a 20% boost in customer satisfaction.

Conceptualised and implemented a streamlined UI/UX design process, reducing development time by 15% and leading to more user-friendly interfaces across web and mobile platforms.

Collaborated as a key team member on LASMAB CMS and Board management app that achieved a 50% improvement in web and mobile system performance, enhancing overall user experience and reducing load times.

# **Experience**

### Full Stack Engineer (Intern)

### **Tech Leaders**

Jun 2023 - Oct 2023 (5 months)

Enhanced automated testing methods, leading to a 20% reduction in testing time and more efficient development processes.

- Achieved 100% efficiency and significantly improved application speed by rigorously testing and implementing program modifications.
- Conceptualized, built, analyzed, and led the deployment of multiple software applications, resulting in increased operational efficiency and user satisfaction.

### **Lead Facilitator and Frontend Developer**

### NUPAT TECHNOLOGIES

Apr 2021 - Present (2 years 8 months)

(2 years 7 months)

- Developed and maintained web applications utilizing a tech stack encompassing HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, React Native, Node.js, and MySQL.
- Collaborated extensively with cross-functional teams to conceptualize, develop, and successfully implement new features and functionalities, enhancing overall product offerings.
- Optimized web application performance for superior speed and scalability, resulting in an improved

user experience.

IBRAHIM ABDULGANIYU - page 1

• Teach and imapact frontend (React and React Native) and backend skills (Nodejs and expressjs) on cohorts.



# Frontend Developer (Mobile and Web))

affilBase

Apr 2022 - Aug 2023 (1 year 5 months) (1 year 4 months)

- Successfully transitioned existing React web applications to React Native, improving user experiences and expanding our mobile presence.
- Meticulously crafted pixel-perfect and seamless user interfaces across diverse mobile platforms, ensuring a consistent and visually appealing user experience.
- Built and published a mobile app, making it available on both the App Store and Google Play Store, broadening our digital reach and impact.

### **Education**



### 関 University of Ilorin

Bachelor's Degree, Social Work

### **Skills**

css • features • html • javascript • mysql • process engineering • web application development • web site production • TypeScript • MongoDB